Guide to the Robert B. Moran Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Robert B. Moran papers
1897-1907
SC0052
Moran, Robert B., 1879-1961.
1 Linear feet
Papers include class lecture notes, personal notes, two diaries of reflections on his trip to California and family background (1886-1900).
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Hugh Moran, 1966.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Stanford undergraduate (1903-1907). Geologist specializing in oil.
Description of the Collection
Papers include class lecture notes, personal notes, two diaries of reflections on his trip to California and family background (1886-1900).
Access Terms
Moran, Robert B., 1879-1961.; Diaries.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Stanford Handbooks containing notes, registrar's receipts, 1901-1903 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lecture notes including notebooks from the following courses: Hstory 4; Geometry; Dynamics; Constructive materials (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lectures notes including notebooks from the following courses: Chemistry 11; Surveying; Latin Composition I (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Westinghouse Electric and Manufacturing Company, Pittsburg, Pennsylvania, Circulars: 1027 May, 1904; 1028 October, 1904; 1079 April, 1904; 1086 July, 1904; 1094 October, 1904; 1098 February, 1905, 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Oil Weekly; Volume 93, number 6, "Peruvian Developments", page 48, April 17, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Felt Lake HR Computations (possibly a term paper), undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Colonial Services of Ancestors of Nathan Montgomery Moran (genealogy), 1897 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Agreement between Mt. Diablo Mill and Mining Company and G. H. Clevenger, et. al. Includes Robert B. Moran as a witness to the agreement. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Laboratory notes on Qualitative Analysis and Physics, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Notes from Physics 2 and Physics 7, Electricity and Magnitism, and other miscellaneous notes. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Class notes from the following courses: German, practive notebook; Linear Drawing, November 7, 1902; Examinations, Physics 1; Chemistry, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Diaries, 1886 Oct-1900 May 8 (Box 2, Folder 5)